It's all right now. Why, you say?
I am here!
He's so cool!
When I get my quirk, I want to
be like this!
You should give up, all right?
Even if that's the case...
How the hell could someone who's a
quirkless loser like you
be on the same level as I am?
What the hell can you do?!
Even if that's how everyone felt...
I'm sorry, Izuku! I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
Ah, no.
No, okaa-san.
I...
Even so, I...
Is it possible to become a hero without
a quirk?
Can someone without a quirk
become a hero like you?
Without a...
Oh no...
Holy shit, damn it!
Because I'm quirkless,
though it may not be because of that, but...
I've been made fun of for a while...
So, I don't know, but...
I think saving people is really cool.
Saving people with a fearless smile...
I also, want to become the best hero like you!
Oh...
At 5 am I held my breath as the silence sunk in
Biting my nails on the fire escape,
what will tomorrow bring?
The day has come
The never-ending night and the never-ending rain
Are all part of this worthless world
"Become a hero too! - Sidekick Recruitment"
Isn't it a little bit off, my feet are
caught up in a slumber
I'm not blaming you
Playing alone in your fantasies
Are you even ashamed of what you imagine there?
A labyrinth, getting tangled inside a labyrinth,
will you still say that you'll go
The sound of the starting bell played by
a little traveler
Where am I headed? Don't know, don't know
Are you really not afraid?
Every step you take can make a change
The day has come
Where am I?
What the heck?
Texas...
- ...Smash!
- Oh right, that bastard.
That bastard, if he hadn't been there...
Katsuki.
Weren't you and Midoriya friends as kids?
You kinda overdid it today.
It's his fault for being in my way.
Hey, don't get irritated about it.
It's just... been my goal since I was little.
That and...
I won't know unless I try.
He's just an idiot holding onto his
childhood dreams.
It makes me angry just watching him!
Well, let's go freshen up at the arcade!
Are you coming too, Katsuki?
Hm... yeah.
Let's go to the station. There are
lots of suckers there.
You're bad.
Ah? If I get caught, it'll affect
my school records!
Ah? Hey, hey!
Hiding such a good quirk!
You deflated!
Eh? Until now.... eh?!
A... a fake?
Skinny!
I am All Might!
No way!
There are guys at the pool who are
constantly flexing their abs...
It's that.
No way!
No... no way!
All Might is fearless...
Always helping with the best smile...
Ah... a fearless smile.
Because you've seen me, shōnen,
don't make the mistake of posting this
on the internet.
Five years ago,
I got this injury from an enemy attack.
Respitory system partially destroyed,
stomach completely removed...
The repeated surgeries and their side effects
have weakened me.
My time limit for hero activities is now...
About 3 hours per day.
That's...
Five years ago...
When you fought Toxic Chainsaw?
You're familar with it.
But that kind of thug won't stop me.
This hasn't gone public yet...
Because I asked them not to publicize it.
The symbol of peace that saves with a smile...
...must never give in to evil!
I laugh to distract myself from the
pressures of being a hero...
And from the fear that rises inside of me.
Pros always risk their lives!
To become a hero without a "superpower..."
...I can't say that it's possible.
If you want to help people...
you can also be a police officer.
They're often the butt of jokes as
the "villain receptionists..."
but that's also a good job.
It's not bad to dream...
But you also have to face reality, shōnen.
Now, hurry up with this guy...
No way...
It's a villain! Which hero's on scene?
To become a hero without a "superpower..."
...I can't say that it's possible.
He kidnapped a child!
That's playing dirty!
What is all this?
I can't grab it!
No!
Death Arms!
Crap!
Hey, stay away from me!
I won't let a sewer man like you
swallow me up!
You little...
Amazing power! This is great, isn't it!
With this quirk,
I can finally get revenge on this kid!
Woah, what is that?
Maybe he's a big-time villain.
She's here!
Rookie Hero Mt. Lady!
Ah, woah, woah!
I need at least 2 lanes to do this.
Explosions are my weakness.
I let someone else handle this.
Ah, thank you.
My hands are full fighting the fire.
Is the fire truck here yet?
What's the situation?
It's sticky, I can't grab it,
And the kid with the good quirk is
struggling and resisting.
Thanks to that it's a minefield.
A triple-threat situation.
Crap!
It's no good! Right now,
nobody here can do this!
We'll just have to wait for someone
with a helpful qurik to come!
Until then, let's limit the damage.
Someone will come soon!
I feel bad for that kid, but he'll have to
endure it just a little bit longer.
Damn it!
If only I had the power to blow
him away...
Hey, doesn't something feel off?
Try your best, heros!
At that time...
I was distracted by my activity timer...
I made this type of mistake while
admonishing my fan...
Pathetic...
I'm pathetic!
- Even in his 3rd year of junior high...
- He still... can't see reality.
- It's time to think seriously about
your future.
- But you have to face reality.
Even a top Pro said it.
Don't cry! You know this is the reality!
You knew it, and that's why you
tried so hard.
Telling yourself you couldn't see it.
This is the explosion from earlier...
Hey, hey...
Did I come here out of habit?
Stop!
It'll just make me feel empty.
Why is he here?
He escaped from All Might?
He dropped it?
If he did...
It's my...
fault.
Why are the heros just standing here?
They can't do anything.
A junior high student was captured.
They've been like that the entire time.
Eh?
Been captured...
the entire time?
And they're able to endure that type of pain?
I thought I'd die within seconds.
Unbelievable...
That villain...
Isn't that the one All Might was
chasing earlier?
All Might? No way! He's here?
I saw him a while ago.
For real?
So then, what is All Might doing?
It's all my fault he can't move...
Pathetic.
Nobody can grab that guy.
We'll just have to wait for a hero with
a helpfull quirk.
Pathetic...
Please do your best... I'm sorry...
I'm sorry...
Pathetic!
Help will be here soon!
Somebody, a hero will come...
Dumbass!
Stop! Stop!
That brat...
Deku?
Why did I go?
Why did I do it? Why?
Explode and die!
What should I do? What should I do at
a time like this?
Page 25!
Kat-chan!
Why you?!
I don't know why, but my legs just
moved on their own.
I think there are many different reasons
- You should give up, all right?
- My... fault.
- ...be on the same level as me?!
- He's a super cool hero!
Kat-chan!
- ...face reality...
- It's been my goal since...
- I'll try my best!
- ...he helps them with a smile...
- But, at that time...
You looked like you needed help.
Stop it!
Pathetic...
I'm pathetic!
Just a little bit longer...
Get out of the way!
This would be a pointless death! Are you
trying to commit suicide?
I'm really pathetic...
All Might...
I admonish you...
...yet I don't even try to do
my part!
Pros always risk their lives!
All Might!
Detroit...
Smash!
Oh... rain?
- No way! Was the wind pressure right now?
- There was an updraft...
Did he make clouds?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
He changed the weather with only his right hand!
Awesome!
So this is All Might!
After that, the heros collected the scattered goop
and safely took it to the police.
Good grief!
That was too much!
You didn't have to take any risks.
The heros scolded me...
On the contrary, Kat-chan was praised.
Amazing toughness! And that quirk!
When you become a pro, come to
our company!
You'd make an excellent sidekick!
I wanted to apologize to All Might, but...
he was being interviewed.
When I get back, I'll try sending him
a message on his homepage.
Deku!
Kat-chan...
I didn't ask for your help...
And you didn't even save me!
I could've done it myself.
Don't look down on me, you quirkless loser.
You think you did me a favor?
Don't look down on me.
Damn nerd!
Toughness...
Kat-chan is right.
I didn't acomplish or change anything.
But, I'm happy.
Now I can have a future that suits me...
I have come!
A... All Might?
Why are you here?
Weren't you surrounded by reporters?
Getting away from them is very easy.
Why?
Because I'm All Migh-
Shōnen, I came here to thank you and
correct myself...
And to make a suggestion.
Eh?
Without you...
If I hadn't heard your story...
...I would've become a fake who's just
all talk and no show. Thanks.
No, it was my fault in the first place.
I got in the way of your work and talked big,
despite the fact I'm quirkless.
Yes...
Because you, a timid, quirkless person unlike
anybody else in that situation...
is what moved me.
Top heros have stories from their days
as a student.
Many of their stories end with,
"My body started moving before I could
even think about it."
Ah...
For whatever reason,
I thought of my mom's words.
- I'm sorry, Izuku...
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
It was the same for you too, wasn't it?
Yeah!
- No, okaa-san.
At that time, what I wanted you to say was...
The words I wanted you to say were...
You can become a hero.
Fiction became reality.
I forgot to tell you...
But this is...
The story of how I became the
greatest hero.
In the world surrounding me and my
uninspired self
Even if I draw it or grasp it, it's
still far away
Woah-oh
I woke up from a dream where no matter how
close I got, it kept going further away
The sunrise starts to shine over the
subdued town
I'm shaking, searching for the meaning of
my existence in the dark
In the world surrounding me and my
uninspired self
Even if I draw it or grasp it, it's
still far away
What do I have to give up in order
to reach it
Because no matter how many times I scream
I am who I am
Whether it's fictional or real
I know I can get through it
It's okay to fall
It's okay to cry
Because someday all of that
Will become a flower
Shōnen, you are worthy
of inheriting my power!
Inheriting your power?
Accept it! My quirk is "One For All."
With this, I can become a hero too?
It's impossible, your body can't keep up with it.
Eh?
Next time: "Roaring Muscles!"
Midoriya-shōnen is gonna become ripped!
Above and beyond,
Plus Ultra!