Let's go!
Ready, go!
No issues found with the engine.
Copy that.
No issues found with the fuel system.
You're Lieutenant Shikishima, right?
I'm Tachibana, from the Tsukuba Naval
Air Group's maintenance squadron.
Do you remember me?
Tachibana-san.
Of course!
Thank you for your help during that time.
Yes.
Wow...
You managed to land that low-quality aircraft
on this hole-filled runway.
As usual, your skills appear to be reliable.
Even though my results in mock ariel combat are good,
going into a real battle with no experience is different.
Luckily, a malfunction in the aircraft
gave you some extra time.
Actually...
No matter how hard I try,
I can't find the error you're talking about.
What are you saying?
Isn't it a good thing?
That we have people like you?
Even if you obey an order like "go die,"
the outcome of this war is already clear.
Give me a gun!
Yes, yes!
An enemy attack?
I'm not sure.
What is it?
Something big!
Is it a new weapon for the US military?
Taki!
It's on the coast!
Copy that!
Taki!
Taki-san!
What is this thing?
It's Godzilla...
It's what?
That's what the guy on the island said.
He said that on days like today when
deep-sea fish float,
Godzilla will come.
Godzilla?
It's no good.
Let's get out of here!
Run!
Hey, hurry up!
Hurry! Run, quickly!
What is that thing?
We're not sure either.
Lieutenant Shikishima!
What is it?
Can you go over there and shoot it with a 20mm?
You're the only person who can shoot it.
We're all just from maintenance squadron.
But wouldn't it be bad if it only gets injured?
No living being can survive being hit by a 20mm!
Hurry up!
Before it gets within attack range!
Hurry, hurry!
Go!
Hurry!
What is he doing?
Now! Shoot!
It's coming this way!
What should we do, Tachibana-san?
Ammo!
Get some bullets!
Idiot!
Don't shoot it!
Stop, you idiot!
Stop!
Get out!
Hurry and get out!
Tachibana-san!
Shoot!
Tomita!
I'll draw it to the front!
Shoot to kill!
How could something like this happen to you...
Hey!
Everyone is dead!
They're dead!
Hey!
It's because you didn't shoot it!
Damn you!
Hey!
Move.
Isn't that loose?
Yes.
Pay attention carefully.
It's going to be a pain if things keep dragging on.
Yes.
Kōichi-san, is that you?
Ōta-neesan!
Didn't you go on a suicide attack?
Eh? Is that not the case?
And you came back with a calm face?
Shame on you!
It's because all the soldiers are cowards
that things are the way they are!
If you guys had stayed strong...
...my children wouldn't have died.
Do you know what happened to my parents?
Everyone died.
This area was surrounded by fire.
Your parents too...
Same fate as my children.
"Come back alive."
That's what you said, right?
You thief!
Move!
Move, move!
Get her!
Move! Move!
Huh?
Please!
Eh?
Stop!
Stop right there!
Eh...
Onii-san!
Finally.
Onii-san, it's your fault.
I can't come pick up the baby
when you're hanging in an area like that.
Have you been here watching this entire time?
I was getting impatient waiting for you to move, okay?
You're hungry, aren't you?
Why didn't you just leave this kid behind?
Hey!
There's no way I could leave her behind in that place!
Eh?
Eh...
Please don't follow me.
If you leave us here like this,
both me and the child will die.
I don't know you!
Once you're done, you're going home.
Scary, isn't he?
Onii-san is heartless.
What happened to your husband?
Was he taken into the army?
Do I look like I have a husband?
Eh?
Then whose kid is that?
It doesn't matter.
That's not a good thing!
During the air raids...
...the child's dying okaa-san asked me to.
So then...
You're not related to that child?
So what?
What are you, an idiot?
You're not in a place to take in a baby like that
and live peacefully!
Even you couldn't abandon it, onii-san.
Hey!
Name?
Your name.
Noriko.
Why do you act like that?
If you're acting like you're a vagrant,
it means you're probably poor.
Are you telling me to become a whore?
Don't give me that look.
In this day and age,
if you're out of options,
then it can't be helped.
What about your parents and siblings?
Your parents?
Yeah.
They both died in the air raid.
You and me are the same, onii-san.
Eh?
He...
Hey!
Wait a...
You...
Hey!
What's with that?
With what?
Don't play dumb.
The parent and the child you picked up.
Who do you think you are,
picking up people like that?
No.
They just showed up and settled on their own.
If you haven't kicked them out,
then you've picked them up.
Hypocrite...
I'm not dealing with this.
Sorry for wasting your time.
Ah...
That kid...
Is she breastfeeding it properly?
Ah, no...
She's...
She's not the child's mother.
What is that supposed to mean?
If things continue like this,
she'll die of malnutrition.
Right?
Picking up a child you're not capable of raising...
What on earth is that all about?
I'm sorry.
It's not for you to eat.
Adults can survive no matter what they eat.
Use this to make gruel for the child.
Ah...
There goes my white rice.
It's annoying, seriously...
Ah, damn it!
I'm soaking wet!
Did you get a job?
I did find something, but...
Eh? What's the problem?
Ah...
The pay isn't bad either.
Check this out..
It seems that just the preperation money
is ¥3000 alone!
That's awesome!
It has to be a scam.
Just the other day,
all the rice that you brought in was stolen.
That's not the case with this.
What's different about it?
It has a stamp of approval from none other
than the Ministry of Demobilization.
There's a reason that it pays so well.
The reason?
During the war,
both the US military and Imperial Navy
secretly laid down mines, right?
It's a job to clean that up.
But the pay is insanely good, because...
Well...
There's...
There's no guarantee that I'll come back alive.
What are you talking about?!
You just made it back alive!
There's nothinng else we can do!
At this rate,
the three of us are going to starve to death!
Even Akiko if it keeps going like this...
I understand that, but...
If we have the money...
If we have the money,
we can even buy powdered milk from America!
For that reason, I'd...
It's no good if you die!
It's okay.
Just becaus it's dangerous
doesn't mean I'm going to die.
It's different from the suicide attacks
of ten deaths and no lives.
And besides,
I'll be on a special ship,
so the magnetic mines won't be able to detect us.
This is...
The special ship?
Hey, you!
Are you our next gunner?
I'm Shikishima.
Are you a boat gunner?
I used to be a fighter pilot.
What?
What's this guy for?
You're a former fighter pilot?
I don't want to be with this
wreck of a military shōnen.
Were you disappointed?
That this is what the ship is like?
The US military and Japan's Imperial Navy laid down
around 60,000 mines along the coast.
Well, there are many different types,
but the most difficult ones
are the US's magnetic mines.
If a ship made out of metal passed by,
it would react and detonate.
So that's why...
He catches on quickly.
Our main job is to clean up moored mines.
To counter magnetic mines,
this wooden boat is the best solution.
I'm Noda.
I developed weapons at the Navy Arsenal
during the war.
This is Captain Akitsu and Mizushima-kun.
This one's "The Kid" and that one's "The Academic
How do you feel about
addressing me like that, chou-san?
And I'm not a kid anymore!
You're still only a beginner,
so being called a kid is more than enough.
Yeah, yeah.
I haven't gone to war anyway.
This is the special minesweeper Shinseimaru.
Paired up with the Kaishinmaru right next to it.
Mines are like balloons that rise from the ocean floor.
We attached cutters to the cables between the
two ships to cut the mines' wires.
That will cause the mines to float to the surface.
So that using this...
it goes DADADADADA!
Watch us.
This one's quite difficult to hit.
Can I do it?
Are you sure?
Because it's shaking...
You have to predict where the bullet will land
before you fire.
Good job!
It's the same as shooting down an enemy plane.
Except, well, I was never in an actual battle.
Eh?
You have no experience in practical combat?
That means Shikishima and I are pretty much the same.
Idiot.
You're completely different.
You can't fly a plane, can you?
If I had gone to war,
I would've been a great help.
Ah, if only it lasted a little bit longer...
Are you seriously saying that?
I'm sorry.
Idiot.
Ah! Stop it!
Shoot it!
Run away!
Evacuate, evacuate!
Are you okay?
A bad dream again?
Dr... dream.
I see...
It's a dream...
Unless...
...you're...
...the dream.
What are you talking about?
Are you okay?
This is Japan, right?
Right?
I'm actually back, right?
I came back, didn't I?
Stop it!
I understand...
I know.
Nice place you built here.
It's worth all of the money you saved up.
Please help yourself.
This is, this is...
May I take one?
Eh?
That's...
That would be a waste of film!
Ah, that smile!
Just like that, just like that...
Yes!
Thank you.
Hey, Academic.
Don't go falling for Nori-chan!
What are you talking about?
Noriko-san is a married woman!
Please stop!
I'm not his wife!
What does that mean?
She settled down here without my permission.
There was nowhere else for her to go,
So I just let her stay here.
Then whose kid is this?
It's her stepchild,
though they aren't blood-related.
She's an orphan that was
entrusted to her during the air raids.
Eh?
Isn't that a touching story in this day and age?
No.
I'm just not thinking ahead.
Otō-chan.
Akiko.
Yes?
I told you.
I'm not your tō-chan.
Shikishima.
Isn't it a bad idea to say that?
It's really unhealthy.
Hey.
Both of you were brought into a family
by fate, and so...
You need to be prepared for that.
Make them happy!
Shut up!
I'm not interested in that kind of thing.
Why?
Welcome back.
I also just returned myself.
What's with your appearance?
How does it look?
I started working as an office worker in Ginza.
I've given you enough money though, right?
I've decided I finally want to be independent.
At this rate, Kou-san,
you'll never find a wife.
Did you know?
Ginza's also recovering very quickly.
Isn't this a bit soon?
I've been thinking about this for a while now.
What about Akiko?
What will Akiko do while you're at work, Noriko-san?
Sumiko-san will take care of her when I'm at work.
Sumiko-san is very enthusiastic about it.
She said, "I've raised 3 children myself."
Well if that's the case,
it's fine then.
Well then,
I'm gonna go get Akiko.
It is estimated that these large sea creatures
will reach the Kantō region of Japan
within a few weeks at latest.
Supreme Commander Douglas McAurthur has
regrettably announced that due to the situation
with the Soviet Union,
military involvement is not possible.
At the same time,
they requested Japan to strengthen all of
it's security agencies.
This...
Was it a giant shark?
A whale?
Sharks and whales can't do this type of damage.
A new Soviet weapon?
Does that look like weapon damage to you?
Then what are you saying?
Something big, like a mountain.
Like what?
You're just acting arrogant even though
you don't understand any of it either.
I was being skeptical until I saw this.
Godzilla.
Please look at that!
Ah?
On the day Godzilla came to the island,
deep-sea fish were floating to the top.
You saw that thing?
It was a monster that looked like
a dinosaur that had survived.
The locals call him Godzilla.
Godzilla?
Foolishness.
Does that type of thing even exist?
You were half-asleep and probably saw an enemy tank-
You probably won't believe me,
but that Godzilla wiped out
the entire garrison on Ōdo Island!
Wait a second...
I thought unit that got wiped out by the US military?
Ōdo Island was ignored by America
during Operation Jumping Stone.
During that time,
it was an emergency landing site
for malfunctioning suicide attack planes.
So then, Shikishima...
Are you a former suicide attack pilot?
If this is the same Godzilla as the one from the island,
it will have grown bigger and more powerful.
Please give me a moment...
Why were we called out here in the first place?
There's no way we're...
gonna have to fight that type of thing, right?
On this type of ship?
That's the case.
Eh?
That type of thing's impossible!
What are we supposed to do with
this kind of petty ship against something
the US military can't even take down?
They told us to stall it.
Stall?
The Takao is coming from Singapore.
Heavy Crusier Takao?
That one?
It was awaiting scuttling,
but it seems that they decided to bring it back.
Isn't that awesome!
The Takao!
I was ordered to buy time until the Takao arrives.
This ship is from America-san, right?
Can't they deal with it themselves?
Things are getting weirder between America
and the Soviet Union right now.
They can't carelessly take military action.
They prefer we handle these types of trivial matters.
Is this a trival matter?
The only weapons we have is a 13mm gun.
They said we could use recovered mines for that purpose.
So that's why they called us out here.
The most important weapons are "locally sourced."
And regarding this,
you are not allowed to tell anyone about it.
There it is.
The usual gag order.
This country never changes!
Can it even change?
Let's swap places.
Thank you.
You're too stuck in your seat, Shiki-san.
To think that the other opponent could be Godzilla...
I know how you feel.
When I think back to the war,
sometimes I also have trouble sleeping.
I want to defeat the enemy.
But at the same time,
I find it incredibly frightening.
There are only two of those,
including a spare.
What's wrong?
The amount of fish on Ōdo Island is nothing
compared to what's happening right now...
Stay on gaurd!
Godzilla is coming!
Here he comes!
Kid, keep your mines ready
to drop at any time!
Yes!
Shikishima, prepare the machine guns.
Let's run away!
We can't fight it on a ship like this!
There's still time!
Let's see how that works out, chou-san!
Academic, keep your eyes peeled and
report back to me.
Chou-san!
Shinseimaru to Kaishinmaru!
It looks like he's about to show up.
Get ready.
We're taking all the credit for defeating the monster.
Those bastards!
Captain!
If we run away now,
the Takao won't make it in time,
so where will the monster head for?
I don't want to see Tōkyō engulfed in flames again.
But this ship is no match for it.
Chou-san, I thought you hated government orders!
Ah, I do hate them!
However...
Someone has to draw the short straw.
This is just impossible.
Academic, engine!
Working on it now!
Shikishima!
Hurry up!
Hurry over here!
Captain!
Got it!
Increase the throttle!
All right!
Drop the mines!
He's almost here!
It's too late!
Even so, we still have to do something!
Now, kid!
Here it goes!
Did it do it?
It's not working!
Oh crap,
Oh crap!
Shikishima!
Machine gun!
Yes!
Shikishima!
No good!
It's useless!
Inside it's mouth!
How about inside it's mouth?
Reel it in, reel it in!
Reel, reel, reel, reel!
Drop it!
Mizushima!
Ignition!
Yes!
Eh?
No way...
No way!
Get down!
Did we kill it?
No!
The Takao!
Just in time.
Crap...
Can you shoot it again?
Did they do it?
What's that?
Have you finally woken up?
Where am I?
This is the Yokosuka Hospital.
You were sent here directly after what happened.
What about the people abord the Takao and Kaishinmaru?
Godzilla...
I see. Where did it go?
It's whereabouts are unknown.
Godzilla was heading towards Tōkyō.
If we don't hurry and issue the evacuation orders,
something bad will happen.
The government will be hiding this
information from the public.
Why aren't they telling everyone now?
Likely due to the fear of causing confusion.
Now isn't the time to say things like that!
If we don't evacuate now, then...
Nobody wants to be held responsible for the chaos
that will inevitably be caused.
Information control is this country's specialty.
What on earth happened?
Noriko-san, it has nothing to do with you.
What's bothering you so much, Kou-san?
With your help,
we've been living together to this day.
And yet I have no part of your life whatsoever?
If you're carrying a burden,
I'd like you to share it with me.
I'm...
...one of the suicide attackers...
...who ran away.
Eh?
On the day of the attack,
I pretended my plane malfunctioned...
...and landed...
...at a landing site on Ōdo Island.
These...
belonged to the maintenance crew there.
All of them died.
On that night,
a giant dinosaur-like monster appeared.
They asked me to shoot it down
with the machine gun from a Fighter Zero.
But I...
I ran away again.
As a result,
all of them were killed by the monster.
They all have should been able to see their families!
The monster was called "Godzilla."
And it appeared again.
But...
Once again, I couldn't do anything.
I'm really a person...
who doesn't deserve to be alive.
Kou-san...
Survivors are supposed to live proper lives.
What do you understand, Noriko-san?!
I understand!
My parents said "Live!" to me
as they were being burned in the fire.
Because of that,
I can't die, no matter what!
That's what I've been feeling.
It's impossible.
Those guys...
Every night, every night,
I dream about them!
"Come up here quickly," they say.
"How do you live your life so proudly?"
Those are dreams.
Illusions created by you, Kou-san.
First of all...
Am I even alive?
I died on that island a long time ago...
Decaying...
Noriko-san and Akiko are looking at the corpse...
That's definently it!
You are alive!
Kou-san is alive!
Don't you understand?
Yes, hold the spoon.
Yes, gently, gently.
Wait, wait...
Yes, now stir the miso soup.
Yep.
Good, good.
Yes, we did it!
Yep!
Raddish. Akiko's favorite raddish.
Raddish.
Please give it a taste.
Yes.
Yes, please.
Drink the soup...
Yes, the raddish.
Delicious.
Hot? Is it hot?
Yep!
Hey, aren't the raddishes delicious?
Yep, delicious!
Hey...
Is it okay if we end this?
I'd like to live again.
Is this an example of...
Hurry up and report it!
Hurry!
Yes!
A costal defense ship from offshore partrol
reported a giant creature heading towards Tōkyō bay.
So, it'll be here soon, won't it?
What's up?
Is this even possible?
Is it here?
Is this really a living thing?
Tōkyō Bay Defense Line,
Should we blow up the 4th district to stop
the unidentified creature from intruding?
Just a little bit more.
It will soon enter the 4th district!
Now!
Detonate it!
Did we do it?
It's no good.
It didn't seem to work.
The blockade of Tōkyō Bay is a failure!
The monster is now heading towards Shinagawa.
It's extremely big!
Thanks.
Breaking news, breaking news!
A giant creature in the Tōkyō Bay
is heading towards Ginza.
If you are in Ginza,
please follow instructions from the police
and begin evacuating immediately.
This is real.
Ginza...
Are you injured?
Hey, what is that?
What happened?
What's up?
That's...
...Godzilla?
An unbelievable sight is unfolding!
An incredibly large creature is
rampaging through Ginza!
The Nichigeki is beying destroyed right now.
All those memories and plays, the Nichigeki...
That Nippon Gekijō is now crumbling before our eyes!
Ah, what a thing to say!
The town of Ginza,
which survived the air raids from the last war,
is now reduced to a pile of rubble!
Ah, what?
The monster is approaching this direction.
Right now,
the face of a giant monster is passing
before our very eyes.
It has become very dangerous here as well.
Hurry and run away!
You're in the way!
Stand up!
Kou-san!
It's no good if you die, hurry!
Hooray!
This is...
...the same as that time.
Noriko?
Nori...
The damaged caused by the creature is around
thirty-thousand killed or injured,
and over twenty-thousand buildings destroyed.
Rescue efforts have been going on since the disaster.
It seems to be difficult to trace the creature
due to the possible risk of radiation.
In addition, around various places in Ginza,
what seems to be the giant creature's flesh has been found
and the police are working night and day to dispose of it.
The center of Ginza is sealed off.
Things have turned out so badly...
What about Akiko now?
When we're in trouble,
we help each other out.
Aki-chan.
Hey.
When your otō-chan isn't around,
you like to come over to your oba-chan's, right?
Where's okaa-chan?
Okaa-chan...
She's away on a trip for work,
so you'll be with your oba-chan for a while.
So you're not going to forgive me?
It's because...
I had a stupid dream.
Shiki-san...
A secret operation to defeat Godzilla
is actually underway.
It's a very unsettling...
...civillian-led initiative but...
Would you like to participate in it?
Everyone here is...
Yes, formerly a marine.
You know a lot.
I'm Hotta, the former captain of the Yukikaze.
As you all know,
Right now, Tōkyō was attacked
by a giant and mysterious creature,
causing an unprecedented crisis.
However,
we do not have a military to protect
the citizens of this country.
It was found that military action from GHQ
would be highly unlikely due to the risk of provoking
the Soviet forces on the continent.
In other words,
We must face that monster with civillian power alone.
It is for that purpose that we have gathered you all here.
As a result of negotiations,
they have promised to provide four destroyers that
that were going to be given to the allies.
Are you...
...saying we have to go on a ship again?
I saw that in Ginza.
I can't beat that type of thing.
After all,
disarmed ships can't fight back properly!
Yeah!
How are we supposed to fight?
Well regarding those matters,
please allow me to explain to you.
Noda-san?
This time...
Sorry about that...
This time, the person who devised the plan...
...is me, former Navy technical officer Noda Kenji.
First of all,
according to the legend from Ōdo Island,
this monster is called Godzilla.
Godzilla takes almost no damage from normal firemarms.
I saw it right before my eyes.
It even got hit by Heavy Cruiser Takao's main gun,
but it quickly regenerated.
So in secret,
I came up with another solution.
First,
I'm going to show you a simple experiment.
The water in here is salt water with
the same concentration as seawater.
This Godzilla-like wood has a weight attached to it
so that it just barely floats.
In this state,
What happens if we pumped freon gas into the tube,
covering the piece of wood with bubbles?
What happens?
Whether or not bubbles comes out,
it'll still float.
Yeah, that's obvious.
That's what you'd think, right?
It sunk!
The bubbles from the freon gas enclose the wood
and prevent it from coming in contact with the seawater.
My plan is that this time, we use this to sink Godzilla,
the monster that attacked Tōkyō, to the bottom of the sea.
Hey,
the Acedemic is a surprisingly awesome guy, isn't he?
As you know,
Sagami Trench off of the coast is more than
1500 meters deep,
an incredible depth for waters off the coast.
Our current plan is to attach
a large number of freon gas tanks to Godzilla,
and at the same time,
have them envelop it with a curtain of foam.
Within a short period of time,
it will sink into Sagami Trench
and the pressure will kill it.
We'll kill Godzilla with the power of the ocean.
This is...
...the outline of Operation Wadatsumi.
That thing came from the see.
It isn't bothered by the deep water pressure.
According to my calculations,
after about 25 seconds,
1500 tons will be exerted per square meter.
Even creatures that can normally survive in the deep sea
cannot with stand these types of rapid pressure changes.
That and...
Can you absolutely kill Godzilla?
There's a lot we don't know about Godzilla's ecology,
so we can only create countermeasures against it
based on our predictions.
That's bullcrap, isn't it?
However, since artillery fire is ineffective,
this is the best solution.
Can you kill him?
Or can you not?
I can't say for sure.
Shikishima!
There is a possibility!
Shiki-san...
Listen until the end!
Now, for a detailed explanation,
Using two destroyers,
we'll wrap the cable around Godzilla.
The cable is already equipped with
a large amount of freon gas tanks.
As soon as it's wrapped around Godzilla,
all of the foam releases,
and Godzilla is pulled down 1500 meters into the deep sea.
But what if that doesn't work?
Then we have a backup plan.
Everyone,
please look at the courtyard.
Deploy!
I'm Itagaki from Tōyō Baloon.
What you just saw is an inflatable floatation device
inspired by the ones installed on former Naval aircraft.
This so-called floating bag gains buoyancy by having
Carbon Dioxide blown into the air sacs.
Now, this can bring Godzilla,
who will have reached the bottom of the ocean,
all the way back up to the surface.
Even if it is able to withstand high pressure,
I don't think it will be able to withstand
the massive decompression that will follow it.
Of course,
I cannot say for sure that we will defeat it.
But the only thing we can do now is what we can.
To all those who survived the war,
I am sorry to ask you to take on a
life-threatening mission again,
but...
I want you to understand.
Now that neither the Japanese government
nor American government can help us out,
we are the only ones who can shape
the future for this country.
It's impossible.
I have a family.
I just can't do it.
That goes for most people here.
Why are we the only ones
drawing the short straws?
I don't want this to be like the war.
Quiet down.
Everyone,
I want you to listen carefully.
This is not an order.
Those with personal situations are free to leave.
We have no right to stop you from doing so.
This...
We're not going to die for sure, right?
Of course not!
Well,
then it's much better than wartime!
Someone has to do it.
It can't be helped, can it?
Without us, the ships won't be able to move.
That's right!
All right!
Let's do it!
Everyone...
Thank you.
But...
I still can't believe you're the one who
planned this type of operation.
I've encountered Godzilla in real life.
That's why they gave me the green light.
They called us in for the same reason, didn't they?
Do you think it'll return?
Due to just recently landing in Tōkyō,
you can see it as an addition to Godzilla's territory.
Worst case scenario...
Godzilla appears again within the next ten days.
That's early!
Apparently,
they've placed lots of radition-detecting buoys.
We can't soley rely on our eyes to detect it.
First off, if you set a trap for it,
are you expecting it to come up and say,
"Oh, it that the case?"
That's it.
Hey, that's impossible.
Please don't make fun of me.
I'm thinking about it carefully.
There's an loudspeaker that's used for
underwater acoustic minesweeping.
Using that,
we'll play back the recorded sound of Godzilla
from his most recent appearance.
The sound of Godzilla?
Yes.
Godzilla will chase after another being because
it'll feel like it's territory is being invaded.
At least he should.
"Should?"
It's always "should."
And what's even the point of that...
levitation-floating-device-thing?
I don't feel like it's gonna work.
Then what are you saying I should do?
Yes, yes!
How about we use a destroyer to pull it up?
Don't say stupid things.
Godzilla weighs around 20,000 tons.
The thrust of two destroyers just isn't enough.
In a nutshell, your plan is full of holes.
If you're going to say those types of things,
then please provide an alternative plan.
Noda-san.
Do you have any connections
to fighter jets somewhere?
Fighter jets?
In the unlikely event it appears on land,
we can anger it with gunfire
and lure it back to Sagami Bay.
After they were disarmed,
all of them were burned down,
the Japanese fighter jets.
Even if there were some left,
it breathes Heat Rays.
Guiding it with an aircraft would be
a very dangerous job.
I don't care if it's dangerous.
Fighter jets are more mobile than ships anyways.
Are you aiming to get shot down on purpose?
Are you just...
Desperate?
Are you drunk?
You just want to avenge Nori-chan.
And you've got a problem with that, don't you?
Now that...
Why didn't you take Nori-chan as your wife
before all this happened?
You knew how she felt about it, didn't you?
I wanted to do that too!
So why?
My...
war hasn't ended.
There were fighter jets?
Yep, but it's a very special one...
It's a local fighter jet designed
near the end of the war
called The Shinden.
Specially designed for hit-and-run bombing attacks.
The maximum speed is over 400 knots.
It has a canard design,
and it's equipped with four 30mm guns.
It's an innovative aircraft
that boasts exceptional weaponary
and incorporates many new inventions.
Apparently, only a few prototypes
were ever actually deployed in combat.
They were deployed here
for the final battle on the mainland,
but they were forgotten about
in the confusion after the war.
Since it was left unattended for so long,
the aircraft often goes rattle-rattle.
I can't fly it like this...
That's the problem.
A good mechanic...
No...
A person who can repair this aircraft
is what we need.
I have a person in mind.
Former Ōdo Island Mechanic Tachibana Sōsaku-san?
Yes.
Tachibana, Tachibana, Tachibana, Tachibana...
He currently doesn't have an address registered.
I see.
We get tons of requests to look for people every day.
It'll take a while for us to find him.
I need to talk to him about some very urgent matters!
You're in a difficult situation.
Even if you say that...
Please!
Just do it!
The survival of the country depends on it!
Even if that's true,
I can't do what's not possible.
I'm sorry.
Well then...
Do you know which unit Tachibana belonged to
before he switched over to Ōdo Island?
I'm doing all that I can...
But I can't get in touch with Tachibana-san.
There are many other excellent
former maintenance personnel.
Why don't you just try a different one?
Please give me a little more time.
Why are you so obsessed with that person?
There's no telling when Godzilla will return.
It's no good if it's not Tachibana!
He's gonna recieve my message soon.
Please!
Tachibana...
Tachibana-san!
It's you, Tachibana-san!
What's the meaning of this?
Ah!
You're saying the deaths on Ōdo Island
were all my fault?
What's up with that?
Sorry...
I knew that if I said that,
you'd get angry and come over here.
Shame on you!
That thing that attacked Ginza...
was...
Godzilla from Ōdo Island.
Our fighter jets need to be upgraded.
That way, I'll be able to defeat it!
I really needed to meet up with you...
so I could ask you do do that!
That's why I sent the fake letters.
Please forgive me!
Do whatever you want.
There's no way I'm gonna help you.
Tachibana-san!
Please wait, Tachibana-san!
Please wait for a second!
Tachibana-san!
There's something I'd like for you to do.
Something that only you can do, Tachibana-san.
I once detonated a mine inside of Godzilla's mouth.
It was far more effective than the guns on the Takao.
He's weak to attacks from the inside.
Do you understand?
You...
I'm going to take a fighter jet full of bombs
and fly it into that thing's mouth.
That will definently kill it!
A suicide attack?
Your war...
...isn't over either.
Ah, so you fell down?
Ow!
It's swelling up again pretty badly.
It's a little embarrassing since I was drunk.
I don't really remember what happened.
Well, it's no wonder you were so excited after
finding Tachibana-san, who you were
very particular about wanting.
A canard aircraft?
I heard rumors about it, it actually was built?
Tachibana-san.
Everyone, thank you for coming!
Are you Tachibana-san?
Is this...
The legendary local fighter jet Shinden?
Yes.
Can you fix it so we can fly it?
We'll try everything we can.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
If you make a face like that, planner-sama,
it's bad for morale.
I know I made this operation, but...
I started to feel like it would
take a miracle for the operation to succeed.
Even so...
The miracle won't happen
if you don't do anything.
That's true, isn't it?
And look at that.
They're smiling.
They aren't idiots.
They know well that this is a tough operation
that risks their lives.
Even so...
Everyone looks so happy.
Maybe this time, they can be helpful.
Be helpful...
We all survived the war.
That's why I said,
"this time."
Hurry up!
Please make room.
1 hour ago,
off of the East Coast of Hacijō Island
at 33°10'N 140°01'E,
It was reported that the installed Geiger counters
have detected a reaction.
And then here and here.
Godzilla's approaching.
Reverse-calculating from this speed,
Godzilla will arrive at the trench off the coast
Sagami Bay at 11:00 in the morning.
In order to confront it,
we will depart tomorrow morning at 8:00.
However...
Will the device be completed by then?
Please take us with you.
The three hours it takes to reach the site are precious.
As an engineer, I want it to be perfect.
But...
You might get stuck in the fight with Godzilla.
We all came back from the war too.
Everyone,
if possible,
please go home tonight
and spend time with your families.
Are you saying to be prepared?
If you think about it...
If you think about it,
this country has wasted too many lives.
Tanks with vulnerable armor...
Due to negligance of supplies,
most deaths in battle
are from starvation and disease.
The fighters didn't even have basic escape methods,
in the end being suicide attacks and gyokusai...
So this time...
I want to be proud of this civillian-led operation
for not having a single casualty.
The battle this time,
It's not a fight to the death.
It's a fight to live in the future.
Let's do it!
It's finally happening tomorrow!
I'm trembling with excitement!
You're not coming with us.
What do you mean?
Well, that arm isn't gonna do you any good.
Shikishima's going too, right?
Is it because I don't have any war experience?
Do you really think I'm useless?
Kid, you're lucky that you didn't go to war.
I want to protect this country too!
Why can't I come with you?
We've been together for a while now!
Please!
Please take me with you too!
I want to go with you too!
I leave this country to you.
Captain!
Noda-san!
See you, Aki-chan.
Thank you for everything.
Akiko.
Did you have fun at oba-chan's house?
It was fun.
I see.
That's good.
Are you giving that to me?
Thanks.
Akiko.
Hmm?
Is this okaa-chan and me and you, Akiko?
Okaa's in it, too.
I see.
You drew it well.
Why are you making that face?
What's wrong?
Akiko.
Hey!
Hey, it's okay!
I'm not going anywhere...
Tachibana-san.
Can you deploy it?
I'll get it ready now.
The ordered bomb.
Two machine guns, 140 kilograms,
120 rounds, 80 kilograms, and...
One of the main fuel tanks,
400 kilograms, was removed.
Instead, this plane was fitted with a No. 25 bomb
in the nose and a No. 50 bomb in the fuselage.
Now, I can finally repay my debt.
It's funny...
I feel like I want to live.
Those who died that day felt like that too.
Everyone wanted to come back alive.
But their wishes weren't granted.
They were killed like insects.
I understand.
The kid who drew this is named "Akiko."
I want you to protect her future.
I'll kill Godzilla no matter what,
even if it means I have to kill myself.
It seems like you finally made up your mind.
All right,
I'm gonna tell you something important.
Look.
This is the bomb's safety device.
Pull it out right before you plunge into him.
Okay?
And...
Aki-chan.
What's wrong? Are you lonely?
Here.
Otō-chan...
Hmm? Otō-chan?
It's okay, it's okay.
This is Kuroshio 12, 35°03'N, 139°41'E.
A bunch of deep-sea fish emerging were spotted!
Godzilla spotted in Sagami Bay!
Currently, we are trying to use an underwater
loudspeaker to guide it to the area of the operation.
Advance schedule for each ship!
Let's hurry up and board the ship!
Let's hurry!
Looks like Mizushima-kun gave up.
I feel bad for him, but it can't be helped.
I actually don't want Shiki-san to fly either.
Isn't Shiki-san a suicide attack survivor?
Seems impossible.
Akiko is here.
He'll definently come back.
Underwater loudspeaker destroyed.
Godzilla has invaded Sagami Bay.
Wadatsumi Squadron, set sail immediately.
Hey!
Over there!
It's here already?
Godzilla breaks through the final defense zone!
Landing is imminent!
I'm leaving!
With this, you're going to end it all.
Shikishima.
Depart from port immediately.
Repeat, all ships of the Wadatsumi Squadron
are to depart from port immediately.
What should we do?
The plan's completely falling apart!
Even so, we'll still set sail.
The missles must be fired from the coast of Sagami Bay,
where they'll have the greatest effect.
All we can do is rely on Shiki-san to lure it.
Yes!
Let's do it!
Noda-san!
It's from Shikishima-san!
This is Shikishima, takeoff was a success.
Now luring Godzilla into the operation area.
We'll be ready soon too.
So let's get to the operation area quickly...
Shikishima!
Don't do anything crazy!
If you leave Akiko all alone,
I'll never forgive you!
Can you hear me, Shikishima?
Damn it, he's ignoring me...
Telegram!
Yes...
Yes?
Are you Shikishima-san?
It's a telegram.
Yes.
That's a big deal!
Godzilla's quite pissed off.
It's in pursuit.
It's our turn, isn't it?
All ships, prepare for battle!
Freon cylinders, all right!
46cm shells, all right!
Floatation device switch, all right!
Concentration cables, all right!
All circuits connected!
Checking power and releasing the safety.
All right, nice!
Unit 1, attack as planned.
As planned!
Nice!
That's...
Godzilla's Heat Ray.
It's impossible to do this type of thing!
Captain!
I recommend evacuating the ship right now!
No. This is good.
Please start the operation immediately.
But when will Heat Ray come again?
As I told you,
Once the Heat Ray is used,
it takes time to regenerate it.
Now!
Please make up your mind!
Operation Wadatsumi begins!
Start to deploy the 46cm shells, cylinders,
and floatation devices!
Shiki-san!
Crane deployed!
Copy that!
Send to Hibiki, maintain course.
Hibiki, maintain course.
I don't mind a little damage,
we're going to maintain this level of speed!
Hibiki approaching, 4 meters.
2 meters.
Brace for impact.
Brace for impact!
Cross complete!
Full speed ahead!
All right...
All right!
Chou-san, switch!
Crap.
Already?
Almost...
Ready...
Chou-san, now!
Cylinder!
All right!
Depth: 1200.
1300.
1400.
Go!
1500.
Target depth reached!
Godzilla has gone silent!
Did we do it?
Stubborn bastard!
Moving to the backup plan.
Do it.
Come up here!
Depth: 1200.
1100!
1000!
The cables have stopped!
They stopped at a depth of 803!
Why?
Why did they stop?
He chewed them all apart.
To Hibiki!
We'll pull from all directions to lift up Godzilla.
Full speed ahead at 90 degrees!
But the thrust of 2 ships isn't enough.
There's no other options!
Do everything you can!
Yes!
If this continues,
the crane won't be able to hold it anymore!
It's no good!
This is the Yokohama Tugboat company's Fujimaru.
We'll do our best to help out.
That voice...
It's Mizushima.
Are you the captain?
Kid! It's you?
Yes!
This is Koeimaru, another ship from Tōyō Kisen.
We, the Nikkōmaru from Yokohama Tugboat Co.,
will cooperate.
Shiokazemaru will assist you.
Tetsuyūmaru.
Nanamimaru.
Minamimaru.
Kisshōmaru.
Junseimaru.
Heimitsumaru.
Tenyūmaru.
Kaiōmaru.
Yūga.
Chōkamaru.
Jūseimaru.
Taramaru.
Yasagamaru.
Please stop calling me "useless!"
All right!
You don't say.
I'm both surprised and impressed with him.
Get the tugboats!
All the ships will pull up Godzilla!
The depth has started increasing!
Come up here, come up here!
Depth: 700.
Raise, raise, raise...
It's not damaged enough!
All ships take evasive action!
What's he going to do?
No way!
That can't be!
It's no good!
Shikishima!
Shikishima...
No, that!
I see...
I see.
The crew member escaped safely.
This seat serves as an escape device.
Pull that lever to activate it.
Live.
Tachibana-san.
Shikishima!
You did it!
Kid!
Sumiko-san!
Kōichi-san!
Kōichi-san...
Akiko...
Eh?
Kou-san, is your war...
Over?