That's awful, Kat-chan!
He's crying!
Any more of this... I... I...
I won't allow it to go on!
You're Quirkless...
...yet still trying to be a hero, Deku!
People are, not born equal.
This is the reality of society that I learned as
a weak 4-year-old.
And... it was my first and last setback.
Wow!
"Midoriya Izuku"
That's a huge villain!
At 5 am I held my breath as the silence sunk in
Biting my nails on the fire escape,
what will tomorrow bring?
The day has come
The never-ending night and the never-ending rain
Are all part of this worthless world
"Become a hero too! - Sidekick Recruitment"
Isn't it a little bit off, my feet are
caught up in a slumber
I'm not blaming you
Playing alone there in your fantasies
Are you even ashamed of what you imagine?
A labyrinth, getting tangled inside a labyrinth,
will you still say that you'll go
The sound of the starting bell played by
a little traveler
Where am I headed? Don't know, don't know
Are you really not afraid?
Every step you take can make a change
The day has come
It all started in China's Qingqing City.
The news was that a glowing baby had
been born.
"Papa"
Ah... ah... ah!!
Since then, "paranormal things" were discovered
in various places.
Time passed by without us ever knowing
the reason.
At some point, "paranormal" became
normal...
...fiction became reality...
About 80% of the world's population...
...has became a society of superhumans
with these unique traits.
In a world full of chaos...
...the job everyone had only dreamed of...
...was now in the spotlight.
This job...
Oh, it's Death Arms!
Upholding justice with his bare arms,
The Punching Hero!
Hey, hey, this is dangerous, ya know.
Get back, get back!
Disaster relief specalist Backdraft is here!
Even so, being able to turn into a
monster is an awesome quirk!
What did he do?
Purse-snatching. After being cornered,
he started acting violently.
Purse-snatching using that quirk...
I'm sorry, the trains...
Eh? I'm not sure when I'll be at the
office, ah...
Yay! Do your best, Kamui!
Stay away from me!
Who's fighting?
Shinrin Kamui!
A young, talented artist who's popularity
is on the rize!
You ask but then explain, nii-chan.
You're an otaku, aren't you!
Uh, no. Hehehe...
Illegal use of abilities during rush
hour and robbery with injury...
The exact embodiment of evil.
Ah! It's coming!
One shot! Show us something flashy, Forest Man!
First strike...
...mandatory binding...
...chained to prison!
Canyon Canon!
Eh...
This is it! This is it!
Wow!
This is it, this is it!
I just made my debut today.
My name is Mt. Lady!
Glad to have a good rear-ationship with you!
Oh, the acknowledgement!
Along with the paranormal, came an explosive
increase in criminal activity.
While the government is hesitant
on changing the law...
...people with courage...
...started hero activities, just like in the comics.
Monitoring the paranormal and protecting
against evil...
Now, heros who have gained citizenship...
...are being made officials due to
pressure from public opinion.
They are rewarded based on their performance.
Money from the government, fame from
the people.
Gigantism?
It seems like she'll become popular,
and she has an awesome quirk, but...
Considering the damage it causes
to the city,
will her actions be limited?
Not if she can control her size...
Hey, hey. Are you taking notes to
become a hero?
Great! Do your best!
Eh... y- yes! I'll do my best!
"Midoriya Izuku: Origin"
Eh... You guys are already in your third year,
so it's time to think seriously about your future.
I'm going to give you print-outs
for career aspirations now...
Most of you want to take the
hero course, right?
Yes!
Ok, ok! Everyone, you all have good quirks.
But using your quirks isn't allowed at school.
Sensei. Don't lump me in with everyone else.
I'm not gonna be dragged down to the bottom
by these quirkless people.
"Bakugō Katsuki"
You've got to be kidding me, Katsuki!
Background characters are background
characters, so shut up!
Ah, surely Bakugō...
...is hoping to get into
U.A. High School.
Isn't U.A. the national school?
This year standard deviation score is 79!
The odds are always so wild, right?
And this is why all of you are
background characters.
I got an A on the mock exam.
I'm the only one on the same level as U.A.
I'll surpass that All Might,
and become the top hero--
My name will definently be engraved on
the list of high-income taxpayers!
Oh, I see. Midoriya also wanted to get
into U.A. High School.
Huh?
Midoriya? That's impossible!
You can't enter the hero industry
just by studying.
Th- That type of rule doesn't exist anymore.
There just isn't a need for it.
- Hey, Deku!
- Ah...
How the hell could someone who's a
quirkless loser like you
be on the same level as I am?!
W... you're wrong! Wait, Kat-chan!
I don't want to compete with you at all!
Really!
It's just... been my goal since I was little.
That and... I won't know unless I try.
What do you mean, "you won't know unless you try?"
Are you screwing with me?!
What the hell can you do?
You're quirkless!
"PM 0:02 the same city"
Ahh!
It's a robber! Somebody!
Catch me if you can!
Ah? There aren't any heros.
Usually someone shows up immediately.
- I guess they took advantage of the morning confusion.
- Hmm?
There are so many people who are
overwhelmed by their quirks.
It's hopeless.
"Hopeless?"
Why is that?
Hm? Oh!
I am here!
- Hey, let's go to karaoke.
- Sure, that's fine.
This morning's incident is at the top of news sites.
I have to hurry up and write that down
in my notebook!
Ah...
We're not done, Deku.
Katsuki? What is that?
Ah? "Hero Analysis for the Future?"
Seriously!
Midoriya!
All right, give it back!
You're terrible!
Most of the top heros have stories
from their days as a student.
I want to have the honor of being the
first and only student...
from this mediocre junior high school.
Well, I'm a perfectionist.
Picky.
- Wh...
- But anyways...
Don't apply to U.A., Nerd-kun.
At least say something back.
Don't say that! Poor little thing.
He still can't see reality.
Ah... if you want to have a quirk that badly,
there is an efficient way.
Believe that you'll have a quirk in
your next life,
and take a one-chance dive off the rooftop!
What?
Dumbass. If I did jump, that would've been
encouraged suicide.
Watch your mouth!
That's not food... idiots.
My notes... idiot.
Dumbass!
Okaa-san!
Okaa-san, the PC!
Again?
Hurry!
You alone have already increased the
view count by 10000, Izuku!
Okaa-san is too scared to watch.
This is an old video...
...from soon after a great disaster that
happened a while ago...
This is one of the hero's debut video.
Can you see it? He's already rescued 100 people!
Holy crap! It hasn't even been 10 minutes!
Holy crap!
He's laughing so hard!
It's all right now. Why, you say?
I am here!
He's so cool!
When I get my quirk, I want to
be this type of hero!
You should give up, all right?
That's... is something wrong?
The kindergarteners are already
showing signs.
It's just this kid...
Excuse me, ma'am, aren't you a 4th generation?
And your quirk?
Eh, of course!
I just attract small objects.
My husband breathes fire.
Normally, at 4 years old,
either one or both of these quirks would appear.
A long time ago, during the early ages of the
paranormal, some research was published
discussing whether or not there is a
joint in the pinky toe.
Humans don't need things we don't use...
Those without it are newer as a "type".
As you can see on this X-ray...
Izuku-kun has 2 joints.
It's rare in this generation, because
he's the type with no quirk.
Can you see it? He's already rescued 100 people!
Holy crap! It hasn't even been 10 minutes!
Holy crap!
He's laughing so hard!
It's all right now. Why, you say?
I am here!
Okaa-san...
No matter what type of trouble, he
helps them with a smile.
He's a super cool hero.
Can I become one too?
I'm sorry, Izuku... I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
Ah, no.
No, okaa-san.
At that time, what I wanted you to say was...
I decided that on that day...
that I wasn't going to worry about
what other people said.
Look ahead, and keep going.
Ah... a villain?
You're an M-size camoflauge suit.
It's okay. I'm just taking over your body,
calm down.
It'll only be painful for about 45 seconds.
I can't... breathe...
I'm a fluid, so there's no way that you
can grab me, now is there?
Very helpful. You're my hero.
No way... I didn't think that that type of
guy would come to the city.
My body... doesn't have the power...
Am I... am I gonna die?
I'm gonna die... somebody...
Somebody... no!
Hm? Ohh!
It's all right now, shōnen.
I am here!
Texas Smash!
The wind pressure...
All... Mi...
Hey. Hey!
Hey... ah?
Thank goodness!
Ah!
I'm glad that you are doing well.
I'm sorry.
I got you involved in a villain extermination.
I don't usually make this type of mistake,
but I just got excited because I was off-duty
and in an unfamiliar place.
Ahahahaha!
- Ah...
- But...
...thanks to you...
I have captured him safely!
Number 1 hero All Might...
It's... it's really him! He looks...
completely different in person!
I see, ah! Autograph...
Autograph, autograph... Uh... Ah!
My notebook!
He signed it!
Wow! Tha... thank you!
I'll treasure it forever!
Okay!
Well then, I'm gonna deliver this
guy to the police.
See you again through the LCD screen!
Eh... that's... already?
Pros are always battling against either
enemies or time.
Wait... I still... wanted to ask you...
In the future...
Please continue to support me!
Eh...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Let go! You're too enthusiastic!
If I let go now, I'll d-die!
Oh, for sure.
I-I-I-I want...
t-to a-ask you d-directly...
I... t-to you...
Okay, okay!
I understand. Now close your
eyes and mouth!
Shit...
Th... that was scary.
Good grief...
If you talk to the people downstairs,
they'll drop you off.
I really don't have time, so this is it.
Wait! Ah...
- No! I don't have time!
- But!
You should give up, all right?
- I'm sorry, Izuku... I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
- What the hell can you do? You're quirkless!
That may be true...
But, even so...
I...
Is it possible to become a hero without
a quirk?
Can someone without a quirk
become a hero like you?
Meeting All Might was a miracle...
It would change my destiny dramatically.
At the time...
I hadn't even imagined it.
In the world surrounding me and my
uninspired self
Even if I draw it or grasp it, it's
still far away
Woah-oh
I woke up from a dream where no matter how
close I got, it kept going further away
The sunrise starts to shine over the
subdued town
I'm shaking, searching for the meaning of
my existence in the dark
In the world surrounding me and my
uninspired self
Even if I draw it or grasp it, it's
still far away
What do I have to give up in order
to reach it
Because no matter how many times I scream
I am who I am
Whether it's fictional or real
I know I can get through it
It's okay to fall
It's okay to cry
Because someday all of that
Will become a flower
In the preview of the next episode...
I am here!
What? The villain that was supposed to have
been captured has escaped?
It's taken a shōnen hostage and is running
wildly around the city?
But my time limit... is running out!
Ugh... you're pathetic, All Might!
Isn't there some hero out there?
Next time: "Hero Requirements"!
Pros always risk their lives!
Above and beyond,
Plus Ultra!
Subtitles by themirrazz