Number 1 hero, All Might.
Unknown age, unknown quirk.
He suddenly appeared in the hero world and
got unshakable popularity for his abilities.
After his appearance...
...the number of severe crimes comitted by
villains decreased each year.
His very existence is considered a deterrent...
and he's a man who became a symbol of peace
in both his name and reality.
And that man, said to me...
You can become a hero.
- Ah? Midoriya?
How the hell could a quirkless
loser like you
be on the same level as I am?!
You should give up, all right?
I'm sorry, Izuku...
What I wanted to be told...
Someone that I admired told me those words.
This type of thing... Is anything as
surprising as this is?
Is anything as...
You are worthy of inheiriting my power.
Eh?
♪～
～♪
In... Inheiriting your power?
What a face you're making! It's a suggestion.
The real action begins here.
Listen up, shōnen. My power...
Will you accept it?
Wh... what the heck are you talking
about, All Might?
I'm talking about my power, shōnen.
In weekly magazines...
they all say it's "superhuman strength"
or "boost."
I've evaded the question on interviews
with jokes.
Because the "Symbol of Peace" All Might...
had to be a naturally-born hero.
However, shōnen, I'll tell you the truth.
My quirk is something that is passed
down like a sacred flame.
Something... passed down?
Yes! And now...
it's your turn!
Wa... ho... wa... hold on a second!
Whether All Might's quirk...
...is one of the seven wonders of the world
is a hot topic for debates!
You almost always see it online!
But, ah, inheiriting a quirk...
I don't really understand that...
I've never heard of that type of thing before.
It's not even speculated about in discussions.
That's because, since the dawn of history,
that type of quirk hasn't been confirmed.
You start in denial.
- Nonsense!
- Ah?
I have many secrets, but I don't lie.
"The power to transfer power..." That is the
quirk I inheirited.
It was given the name "One For All."
One For All...
Yes.
1 person gains power...
...who passes it on to another who
gains power and passes it on again.
And so, the voices crying for help and
the brave souls have been woven together.
A crystal of power.
That's so important... Why...
Why would you give that to me?
I was originally looking for a heir,
and I thought I could give them to you.
You, an ordinary quirkless hero lover...
more than anyone else at that moment...
were a hero.
Just kidding.!
Though, it's just up to you.
What do you say?
He told me this much...
Revealing a big secret to me...
Are there? There's none, right?
There aren't any!
There are... no reasons to refuse!
Please!
An immediate answer.
I thought you'd say that.
However, recieving power...
was not something easy.
Hey, hey, hey!
What a comfortable fridge to sit on!
Had it moved even a tiny bit...
it would've been a little more comfortable.
Well,
that's because you weigh 274kg, right, All Might?
No, I lost weight. I'm 255 kilograms...
In this form.
By the way, why I am hauling trash around at
a beach park.
That's that.
You're not a vessel.
Eh? That's the exact opposite of what
you said earlier!
Your body, it's your body!
Ah?
My quirk, One For All,
is like the ultimate phyiscal
abilities of many people
combined into one.
A weak body can't handle it.
Your limbs would get torn off and explode.
Limbs torn off?!
So, I'm picking up trash to train my body?
Yes! But that's not all.
I looked it up online. This beach park...
The coastline has been like this for years!
Yeah...
There's lots of floating debris due to the
ocean currents or something...
People take adventage of this, so illegal
dumping is also rampant here.
Even the locals don't come here.
The best heros just pursue flashiness.
But originally, heros were volunteers.
Even if people say that it's plain,
we can't waver from that.
You will revive the entire horizon
of this area.
That's your first step in becoming a hero.
My first step...
is cleaning this?
全部？
Midoriya-shōnen, you aspire to go
to U.A., right?
Yes... Yes!
U.A. is the school you went to, All Might,
so if I go, it definently will
be U.A.!
Proactive otaku!
But as I said earlier...
It's not a job you can do
without a quirk.
Sadly, that's the reality.
In addition, U.A. has the most
difficult hero course.
In other words...
I have 10 months left before the entrance
exam to finish becoming a vessel.
That leads to this!
My idea: "The Aim-For-Success
American Dream Plan!"
It's a training plan to make
cleaning up trash more efficient.
Your entire life will follow this schedule.
Even your bedtime...
Honestly, this is super hard.
Can you keep up with it?
Of course...
I have to work harder than other people,
or I'm no good!
And this is how my 10 months of hell began.
Bring it to the park entrance!
Load it into the truck!
Depending on the shape and size,
completely different muscles are used.
I see, this is...
Run, run!
10 months is just around the corner!
Let's be athletic!
Eh... along with the paranormal,
revisions to the Build Standards Act
are underway...
It's intense... 10 months of this?
It's gonna be tough if I don't finish
it 1 week before the enterence exam,
so I have 294 days left.
Taking muscle recovery into account...
So let's say there's an interval
of about 2 days.
Even if I do it efficiently, the
actual training takes about 98 days.
5 hours of traning, in the morning
and the evening...
490 hours.
Also, cleaning trash isn't about training
specific parts of the body...
I have to train my whole body evenly,
or there's no way I'll make it in time.
Building a body that can adapt
to any situation...
This is the exact type of training I
need to become a hero.
All Might won't always be watching
over me, either...
Midoriya, hey!
Did you damage your head in the
encounter with the villain?
If something like that happened, it's
arrogant for you to even mention U.A.
Plus, preparing for the exam...
Is he going psycho already?
Scary...
Sometimes when anything doesn't go well
I believe in what I've been working on
Do what you like, just give me one thing
I see the future, don't miss out now
Hero is in my heart, hero is in your heart
I don't care whatever people say
I can be a hero, you can be a hero
If you wanna make it just try hard
I know I'll be suffice you
Hey, hey, what's wrong? There's
only 3 months left!
You won't make it at all.
Are you gonna quit? Take it
easy today?
Overwork?
The "Aim-to-Pass American Dream plan"
I thought I had adjusted it
to fit your body so you could
complete it in time for the enterance exam...
You aren't sticking to the plan, are you?
Overdoing it will only be counter-productive.
Don't you want to pass?
I want to.
But it's just not enough to get it.
うん？
I have to work way harder than other people,
otherwise I won't be able to keep up.
I want to be like you!
To become the best hero!
Saving people with a fearless smile...
Like you.
He's looking far into the future!
You proactive otaku!
I don't dislike that type of thing.
But if that's the case, you shouldn't
be in a hurry anymore.
But I got the setiment.
Oji-san will adjust the plan a bit.
All Might... isn't oji-san...
So, at 6:00 am on the day of the exam...
Hey, hey, hey...
Even beyond the designated area...
For real? There's not even a speck of dust left...
Is this for real?
He more than finished it
at the last minute...
All Mi... All Mig...
Goodness!
Good job!
All Mihgt... I did it...
I did it.
Ah, I'm surprised.
You entertainer! Being a teenager
is wonderful!
- Check this out!
- This is...
- You from 10 months ago.
Good job, really!
The mirage of getting in has just
barely came into view...
But you now are certainly a vessel!
I feel like I'm cheating somehow...
All Might... thank you for helping
me out like this.
You're too kind.
What's the deal now? It's your
own hard work.
You need to fix that crybaby behavior.
Now, the award ceremony, Midoriya Izuku!
Yes!
This is something I heard somewhere,
It's important to remember that those given something
by chance and those given something by recognition,
their essences are different from
each other.
This is the power that you have earned.
A reality more surprising than the comics...
I also grabbed onto one.
Eat it.
Huh?
As long as you intake my DNA, it
doesn't matter what it is.
That's completely different from what
I expected!
Well, there's no time.
You'll be late for the exam!
- Here, here!
- Wah...
- Here!
- Waaaaaaaaaaah!
Just in time.
In the end, I didn't have time to try
the power I got from All Might.
Eat it!
I ate it, but I wonder if it
really worked.
Move, Deku!
Kat-chan!
Don't stand in front of me,
or I'll kill you.
Uh... G-good morning, pl-please
try your h-hardest!
Hey, look, isn't that Bakugō? From during the slime?
Wow, it's really him!
Since that day, Kat-chan hasn't done
anything to me.
It's already a habit for me to
get scared like this.
I'm different from before.
Remember the past 10 months.
Take...
my first step to becoming a hero!
This...
Are you okay?
It's my quirk.
Sorry for using it without your permission,
but if you fell it would've been
bad luck.
I'm so nervous...
Eh... Ah... Uh...
Please try your best! Bye!
I talked to a girl!
"Didn't Talk"
Exam canidate listeners...
Welcome today to my live!
Everybody say "hey!"
"Silence!!"
You're all chill.
So, to the exam canidate listeners...
I'll give you a quick presentation
of the practical exam.
Are you ready?
Yeah!
"Silence!!"
It's voice hero Present Mic!
Awesome!
I listen to his weekly radio! I'm touched!
All of the instructors at U.A. are
professional heros!
Annoying.
According to the entrance exam guidelines,
listeners will participate in a
10-minute mock city excercise!
Feel free to bring anything.
After the presentation, head over to your
designated training venue.
"Silence!!"
Okay?
So in other words, they don't want
friends helping each other out.
Really...
Are exam numbers are consecutive, but we're
in different training venues!
Don't look or I'll kill you!
Tch, I can't crush you.
The training grounds have 3 types of
virtual villains deployed.
You will earn points based off of each
of their difficulty levels.
Each player incapacitates the virtual villain
with their own quirk
Your goal is to earn points, listeners.
And of course, attacks on others
and anti-hero actions are prohibited.
Can I ask a question?
Okay!
There are 4 types of villains listed
on this printout.
If it's a misprint,
it will be a shameful act for U.A.,
Japan's best school!
We as test takers are sitting here
to seek guidance from examplary heros!
And you with the crazy hair!
Eh?
Your mumbling to yourself is distracting!
If you're just sightseeing, leave here immediately!
Excuse me...
Okay, okay!
Canidate Number 7111-kun.
Nice letter, thank you!
Villains in category 4 are 0 points.
They're pests.
They're gimmicks that cause mayhem
throughout each venue.
They're not impossible to beat,
but there's no point in doing so.
Listeners, I recommend you avoid it.
Thank you! I'm sorry!
I see. It's a stage gimmick that can
be avoided.
It's like a game, this is.
That's all from me.
Finally, to the listeners, let's present
our school motto.
The hero Napoleon Bonaparte said,
"A true hero is the one who overcomes the misfortunes of life."
Above and beyond,
Plus Ultra!
And everyone, have a good time!
I... I'm doing it...
What All Might trained me to do...
What I achieved in the past 10 months...
I'll give it my all...
I'll become...
the hero I've always wanted to be!
A prestigious school that has yielded
many pro heros,
the U.A. enterance exam begins.
Using only the quirk I inheirited
from All Might,
can I survive the practical exam?
Let's all do our best on
the enterance exam please!
Eh? Who's that?
More like, I talked to a girl!
Next time: "Start Line."
Ochako-san shoots sparkly stuff out of her mouth.
Above and beyond,
Plus Ultra!
Subtitles by themirrazz